Guide to the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VII: Projects
  - Subseries VII.V: International Mind Alcoves, 1922-1946
    To increase the material on international relations available to the American reading public the Endowment established International Mind Alcoves in selected American libraries in 1922. Alcoves were established in selected public libraries in small communities throughout the United States and in a number of State libraries. Each Alcove was sent a collection of books on international relations four times a year, until a total of approximately one hundred volumes had been distributed, at which time the library was dropped from the list and another added. The Endowment discontinued the systematic distribution of books to the International Mind Alcoves in 1948.
    - 1919-1946 (Box 306)
    - Photographs (Box 306)
  - Subseries VII.W: International Relations Centers, 1925-1948
    These files on International Relations Centers are composed primarily of the reports sent to the Endowment by the various regional centers of peace organizations. These reports are summaries of the individual projects that were undertaken and developed through the different centers. The files also contain correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, mimeographed matter, radio scripts, and leaflets.
    - 1925-1941 (Box 306)
    - 1942-1943 June (Box 307)
    - 1943 July -1945 April (Box 308)
    - 1945 May -1948 undated (Box 309)
    - Photographs (Box 309)
    - Publications, 1930-1935 1940-1947 undated (Box 310)
  - Subseries VII.X: International Relations Clubs, 1927-1948
    The International Relations Clubs were groups of students organized under the auspices of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace in universities, colleges, and normal schools for the study of international relations. Two publications were issued by the Endowment for the IRC's: "The Fortnightly Summary of International Events" and a Spanish edition called the "Resumen. "
    In January 1932 there were 384 active International Relations Clubs. There were clubs in every state of the Union, in the Philippines, and in Puerto Rico, and clubs in China, Japan, Iran, Australia, New Zealand, and the Union of South Africa, Canada, the British Isles, and Latin America. By 1947 there were 842 college clubs alone, offering guidance to approximately 25,000 to 30,000 students in international relations.
    - Correspondence
      - 1922-1926 (Box 310)
      - 1927-1949 (Box 311)
    - General file, 1927-1948 (Box 311)
    - Sample letters, 1926-1928 (Box 312)
    - Sample club material (Box 312)
    - Applications (with photographs when available), 1929 (Box 312)
    - General Information on Model Assembly of the League of Nations, 1927 (Box 312)
    - Lists of IRC, 1933-1940 (Box 312)
    - Maps (Box 312)
    - Noticias de las Centros de Relaciones Internacionales, 1922 1934-1937 (Box 312)
    - Photographs (Box 312)
    - Printed matter, 1908 1925-1929 1934-1944 (Box 312)
    - Reports, bulletins, etc. (Box 313)
  - Subseries VII.Y: International Visits
    - General file, 1930-1945 (Box 313)
    - Argentines, 1933 (Box 313)
    - Bonn, Dr. Moritz J., 1929 (Box 313)
    - Cambridge University Medical Society, 1926 (Box 313)
    - Craigmyle, Lord, 1932 (Box 313)
    - Cryan, Mrs. Amy, 1926-1927 (Box 313)
    - Educators
      - British Educators to the U.S., 1932 (Box 313)
      - Chilean Educators to the U.S., 1934 (Box 313)
      - U.S. Educators and Agriculturalists to South America, 1941 (Box 313)
    - Einstein, Louis, 1923-1924 (Box 313)
    - Gaede, Dr. William, 1946 (Box 313)
    - Interparliamentary Union members to the U.S. in 1925 (Box 313)
    - Jackh, Dr. Ernst, 1930-1931 (Box 313)
    - Journalists
      - American journalists to Europe, 1927
        - 1926-1927 July (Box 314)
        - 1927 Aug-Dec (Box 315)
      - British journalists to the U.S., 1928
        - 1928 Jan-Aug (Box 315)
        - 1928 Sept-Dec (Box 316)
        - Publications, photographs, clippings (Box 316)
      - European journalists to the U.S. (1929)
        - 1928-1929 April (Box 316)
        - 1929 May -Dec (Box 317)
        - Publications and clippings (Box 317)
      - U.S. journalists to the Orient, 1929 (Box 317)
    - Marley, Lord, 1936 (Box 318)
    - Mexican architects, 1931 (Box 318)
    - Morocco and Algiers, 1923 (Box 318)
    - Nelson, Dr. Ernesto, 1927 (Box 318)
    - Oehler, Richard, 1930 (Box 318)
    - Phillips, Mr. & Mrs. Clarence, 1931 (Box 318)
    - Professors of Internal Law and Relations to Europe (1926)
      - 1925 Dec-1926 (Box 318)
      - 1927 (Box 319)
      - Publications (Box 319)
    - Romanians to the U.S. (1926) (Box 319)
    - Tomlinson, John D., 1937 (Box 319)
    - Ulloa, Alberto, 1926-1949 (Box 319)
    - University of Puerto Rico Debating Team, 1930-1931 (Box 319)
  - Subseries VII.Z: Library aid and special gifts of books
    - American Book Center for War Devastated Libraries, 1945-1948 (Box 319)
    - American literary and historical books presented to British universities, 1926 1927 1936 (Box 320)
    - Anthens College (Greece), 1944-1947 (Box 320)
    - Charles University (Prague), 1926 (Box 320)
    - City of Tallinn (Estonia), 1929 (Box 320)
    - City of Tokyo, 1921 (Box 320)
    - Empire Parliamentary Association, 1944-1045 (Box 320)
    - Funk, E.M., 1926 (Box 320)
    - Hague Library at the Peace Palace, 19443-1947 (Box 320)
    - Konsullarakademie (Austria), 1931 (Box 320)
    - Library for American Studies in Italy, 1943 (Box 320)
    - Library of Congress (USA), 1943 (Box 320)
    - Meiji University LIbrary Committee, 1924 (Box 320)
    - National Library of Bogota, 1947-1938 (Box 320)
    - Pentre, Rhonda, South Wales, 1919 (Box 320)
    - Public Library in the Dominican Republic, 1935 (Box 320)
    - Reims (France), 1922-1923 (Box 320)
    - Spain, gift of 50 books to, 1942-1943 (Box 320)
    - Sydney (Australia) Department of Education, 1941 (Box 320)
    - Université de Strasbourg, 1921-1922 (Box 320)
    - University of California-gift of Latin-American studies book, 1943-1945 (Box 320)
    - University Library, Belgrade, 1919-1923 (Includes photographs.) (Box 320)
    - University of Western Australia, 1920-1931 (Box 321)
    - Zentralbibliothek, Zurich, 1933 (Box 321)
  - Subseries VII.AA: Louvain Library
    The Carnegie Endowment made the initial contribution of $100,000 to the fund for the reconstruction of the Library of the University of Louvain, which was destroyed in World War I. The reconstuction was completed, but the structure was subsequently destroyed in the Second World War.
    - 1918-1930 1940-1947 (Box 321)
    - Publications, photographs, clippings (Box 321)
  - Subseries VII.BB: Notes and Forecasts, 1947-1949
    - Notes and Forecasts, a fortnightly mimeographed analysis of the major United Nations trends and activities, was developed by the Endowment at the request of a number of observers from organizations accredited to the United Nations who found it difficult to follow all the current developments in the different fields of activity. It provided information not easily available by utilizing a number of sources such as unpublished documents, conversations with members of delegations or the Secretariat, and research on specific topics. It also forecasted future developments within the United Nations. The newsletter was provided without charge as a service of the Endowment to officers and staff members of organizations concerned with the activities of the United Nations, libraries, colleges, editors, lecturers, broadcasters, the State Department, and the United Nations. (Box 321)
  - Subseries VII.CC: Orient
    These files include correspondence and reports dealing with Endowment activities in the Orient and correspondence from individuals in the Orient informing CEIP of their activities.
    - General correspondence, lectures, articles regarding the Orient, 1920 1929-1946 (Box 322)
    - American School in Japan, 1927-1929 (Box 322)
    - American School in Tientsin, 1923 (Box 322)
    - Baja, Tiburcio C. (Philippines), 1944 (Box 322)
    - Butler message to Japan, 1930-1935 (Box 322)
    - Caracristi, Charles, 1942 (Box 322)
    - Chinese National Association of the Mass Education Movement, 1930 (Box 322)
    - Condliffe, J.B., 1930 (Box 322)
    - East and West Association, 1944-1947 (Box 322)
    - Greene, Jerome, 1930 (Box 322)
    - International library in Shanghai, 1930 (Box 322)
    - Investigation of civilian bombardment in China, 1937 (Box 322)
    - Japanese-American Citizen's League, 1944-1945 (Box 322)
    - Jessup, Phillip, 1942-1943 (Box 322)
    - Kawakami, K.K. (Japan), 1924 (Box 322)
    - Laboratory for Educational Research in China, 1925 (Box 322)
    - Lasker report-Oriental Influences on American Life, 1930 (Box 322)
    - Legendre, A.F., 1929 (Box 322)
    - Loomis, Francis, 1924-1925 (Box 323)
    - Miyazaki, M. (Japan), 1931 (Box 323)
    - Monroe, Paul, 1926 (Box 323)
    - Moore, Frederick, 1926 (Box 323)
    - Oka, Minoru (Japan), 1929 (Box 323)
    - Orr, Mark T., 1932 1946 (Box 323)
    - Pearson, Drew, 1924 (Box 323)
    - People's Foreign Relations Association of China, 1941 (Box 323)
    - Reports on conditions in China, 1924 1929 1930 1937 (Box 323)
    - Statements on the Sino-Japanese conflicts, 1931-1932 (Box 323)
    - Thomas, Elbert D., 1925 (Box 323)
    - Yuan, T.L. (China), 1935 1938 (Box 322)
  - Subseries VII.DD: Rejected Projects, 1952
    - A-L (Box 323)
    - M-U (Box 324)
    - University of Virginia-Institute of Public Affairs (Box 324)
    - V-Z (Box 324)
  - Subseries VII.EE: Stresemann Memorial, 1930-1931 1939
    - On June 21, 1930 Dr. Julius Curtius, then German Minister of Foreign affairs, made a radio address from Berlin, which was broadcast throughout the United States. Dr. Curtius announced the intention of the German people to found a Peace Academy as a memorial to the late Dr. Gustav Stresemann. The Carnegie Endowment made a grant of 100,000 Reichmarks (ca. $25,000) as a contribution in support of this memorial. (Box 324)
  - Subseries VII.FF: United States Summer Schools, 1915
    During the summer of 1915 courses in international affairs and relations were offered at forty-two universities, twenty colleges, and sixteen normal schools in the United States. The Endowment supported many of these programs.
    - Baylor University (Box 324)
    - City of Birmingham, Ala. (Box 324)
    - Butler College (Box 324)
    - University of California (Box 324)
    - University of Colorado (Box 324)
    - Dartmouth College (Box 324)
    - Delaware College (Box 324)
    - University of Denver (Box 324)
    - DePauw University (Box 324)
    - Drake University (Box 324)
    - East Central State Normal (Oklahoma) (Box 324)
    - Fairmount College (Box 324)
    - Fayetteville, Arkansas (Box 324)
    - University of Florida (Box 324)
    - University of Georgia (Box 324)
    - University of Illinois (Box 324)
    - Indiana University (Box 324)
    - University of Kansas (Box 324)
    - Lincoln Memorial University (Box 325)
    - Manual Training High School, Kansas City, Missouri (Box 325)
    - Mercer University (Box 325)
    - Michigan State Normal College (Box 325)
    - University of Mississippi (Box 325)
    - University of Missouri (Box 325)
    - Missouri State Normal School (Box 325)
    - University of Montana (Box 325)
    - University of North Dakota (Box 325)
    - North Texas State Normal College (Box 325)
    - University of Oregon (Box 325)
    - Pacific Unitarian School for the Ministry (Box 325)
    - University of Pennsylvania (Box 325)
    - Rutgers College (Box 325)
    - University of Southern California (Box 325)
    - Stanford University (Box 325)
    - State Normal School, California (Box 325)
    - State Normal School, Noth Dakota (Box 325)
    - State Normal School, West Virginia (Box 325)
    - State Teachers College, Colorado (Box 325)
    - University of Texas (Box 325)
    - University of Vermont (Box 325)
    - University of Virginia (Box 325)
    - State College of Washington (Box 325)
    - West Texas State Normal College (Box 325)
    - West Virginia University (Box 325)
    - Winona State Normal School (Box 325)
    - Wooster Academy, Ohio (Box 325)
    - University of Wyoming (Box 325)
  - Subseries VII.GG: Vatican Library, 1926-1937
    The Endowment cooperated with the Vatican Library to catalog and classify its imanuscripts, incunabula, and printed books. After a general survey of this project had been made and a plan of re-organization outlined by United States librarians in consultation with Vatican authorities, several members of the staff of the Vatican Library spent time in the United States to become familiar with modern methods of library science.
    The files include letters and detailed reports of Dr. William Bishop, Cardinal Tisserant, Cardinal Gasquet, Cardinal Mercadi, and Cardinal Ambraeda, as well as general correspondence.
    - 1926-1930 (Box 325)
    - 1931-1948 (Box 326)
  - Subseries VII.HH: Visiting Carnegie Professors, 1927-1947
    The Division of Intercourse and Education appointed distinguished scholars to visit and to lecture at educational institutions in a country or countries other than their own as representatives of the Endowment. The purpose of the visits was to strengthen the bonds of intellectual and scholarly understanding and friendship between the various countries. No formal program was prescribed by the Endowment; the actual plans for the professorship were, in most cases, made by correspondence directly between the visitors and the authorities of the institutions he visited.See also Series I.N. Green cover reports (Box 105) for Visiting professors' reports.
    - General file
      - 1926-1936 (Box 326)
      - 1937-1948 (Box 327)
    - Individual Professors
      An asterik denotes the presence of the report on the individual’s visit.
      - Adams, Randolph G., 1928-1929 (Box 327)
      - Altamira y Crevea, Rafael, 1937-1945 (Box 327)
      - Ames, Sir Herbert, 1937-1938 (Box 327)
      - Arnaud, Leopold, 1942-1943 (Box 328)
      - Averardi, Bruno, 1929 (Box 328)
      - Barlow, Samuel, 1943 (Box 328)
      - Barrows, David P., 1927 (Box 328)
      - Bemis, Samuel Flagg*, 1936-1941 (Box 328)
      - Blakeslee, George H., 1927 (Box 328)
      - Bogert, Marson T., 1927-1932 (Box 328)
      - Booth, Charles, 1932-1938
        - 1932-1934 (Box 328)
        - 1935-1938 (Box 329)
      - Bouniatian, Mentor, 1938 (Box 329)
      - Calhoun, George M., 1927 (Box 329)
      - Castillejo, Jose*, 1937-1942 (Box 329)
      - Chamberlain, Sir Austen, 1931 (Box 329)
      - Chevrillon, Andre, 1929 (Box 329)
      - Coffman, Louis D., 1931 (Box 329)
      - Cole, Percival R., 1929-1936 (Box 329)
      - Coulter, Charles W., 1929 (Box 329)
      - Coudenhove-Kalergi, Count, 1941-1944
        - 1941 (Box 329)
        - 1942-1944 (Box 330)
      - Cybichowski, Sigismund, 1929-1938 (Box 330)
      - Dávila, Carlos, 1939 (Box 330)
      - Delgado, Carlos, 1932-1933 (Box 330)
      - Dengler, Paul*, 1932-1938 (Box 330)
      - Digeon, M., 1939 (Box 331)
      - Duniway, Clyde, 1929-1931 (Box 331)
      - Dutcher, George M., 1929-1930 (Box 331)
      - Encinas Franco, Jose Antonio, 1936-1938 (Box 331)
      - Fation, Guillaume*, 1935 (Box 331)
      - Faust, Albert*, 1932-1933 (Box 331)
      - Ford, Walter, 1929 (Box 331)
      - Garner, James, 1929 (Box 331)
      - Geshkoff, Theodore, 1931-1938 (Box 331)
      - Greig, John Y.T., 1929-1930 (Box 331)
      - Hadley, Arthur, 1927 (Box 331)
      - Hanke, Lewis, 1938-1939 (Box 332)
      - Hanotaux, Gabriel, 1923 (Box 332)
      - Harlow, S. Ralph, 1937-1938 (Box 332)
      - Hayden, J.R., 1930-1931 (Box 332)
      - Heyrovsky, Jaroslav, 1932-1933 (Box 332)
      - Hilka, Alfons, 1930 (Box 332)
      - Hill, David, 1927 (Box 332)
      - Jackh, Ernst, 1926-1930 1944-1945 (Box 332)
      - Kilpatrick, William, 1929 (Box 332)
      - Knickerbocker, William, 1935-1936 (Box 332)
      - Lacour-Gayet, Robert*, 1943-1945 (Box 332)
      - Labaree, Leonard W., 1929-1930 (Box 333)
      - Lafronte, Viteri, 1945 (Box 333)
      - de Lanux, Pierre, 1938-1939 (Box 333)
      - Listowel, Judith, 1937 (Box 333)
      - Llewellyn, Karl L., 1929 (Box 333)
      - Lodge, Oliver, 1943 (Box 333)
      - Loewenstein, Hubertus*
        - 1936-1944 (Box 333)
        - 1945-1948 (Box 334)
      - Lojendio, Ignacio, 1943-1947 (Box 334)
      - Macchioro, Vittorio, 1930 (Box 334)
      - Magill, Rosewell, 1936-1937 (Box 334)
      - Martin, Charles E., 1928-1931 (Box 334)
      - McBride, George, 1929-1938 (Box 334)
      - McGuire, Constantine*, 1941 (Box 334)
      - McGuire, Martin, 1941 (Box 334)
      - McMurry, Donald L.*, 1932-1933 (Box 334)
      - Mears, Eliot G.*, 1929-1932 (Box 335)
      - Mills, Richard C., 1929-1931 (Box 335)
      - Mims, Edwin, 1935-1939 (Box 335)
      - Molyneaux, Peter, 1941 (Box 335)
      - Montague, William, 1927 (Box 335)
      - Montenegro, Ernesto, 1939 (Box 335)
      - Morgenstern, Oskar, 1937-1938 (Box 335)
      - Mowat, R.B., 1941 (Box 335)
      - Munro, Dana G., 1934-1936 (Box 335)
      - Muzzey, David S.*, 1936-1937 (Box 335)
      - Nakaseko, Rokuro*, 1929 (Box 335)
      - Nevins, Allan*, 1941-1944 (Box 335)
      - O'Gorman, Edmundo, 1941-1942 (Box 336)
      - Ozaki, Yukio, 1931 (Box 336)
      - Padilla, Guillermo, 1943-1944 (Box 336)
      - Paish, George, 1936-1937 (Box 336)
      - Peers, E. Allison, 1938-1943 (Box 336)
      - Pelenyi, John, 1941 (Box 336)
      - Politis, Nicolas, 1941 (Box 336)
      - Porter, Livingstone, 1930 (Box 336)
      - Pratt, Julius, 1937-1938 (Box 336)
      - Raestad, Arnold, 1933 (Box 336)
      - Ravignani, D. Emilio, 1937 (Box 336)
      - Rojas, Ricardo, 1930 (Box 336)
      - Sadler, Michael, 1929 (Box 336)
      - Samuel, Herbert, 1933 (Box 337)
      - Schlesinger, Arthur M., 1933 (Box 337)
      - Schneider, Herbert W., 1935 (Box 337)
      - Sforza, Carlo*, 1929-1943
        - 1929-1941 (Box 337)
        - 1942-1943 (Box 338)
      - Shepherd, William R., 1932 (Box 338)
      - Siegfried, Andre, 1934-1935 (Box 338)
      - Slosson, Preston*, 1931-1939 (Box 338)
      - Slusser, Herbert, 1929-1930 (Box 338)
      - Stuart, Graham H., 1929 (Box 338)
      - Sturtevant, Alfred H., 1932-1933 (Box 338)
      - Suzzallo, Henry, 1928-1929 (Box 338)
      - Teleki, Paul, 1936 (Box 338)
      - Tello, Julio C., 1928 (Box 338)
      - Thompson, Walter, 1930-1932 (Box 338)
      - Tinker, Edward, 1941-1945 (Box 338)
      - Twentyman, Arthur E., 1929-1931 (Box 339)
      - Villard, Leonie*, 1936-1937 (Box 339)
      - de Villers, C.G., 1934-1935 (Box 339)
      - Wachtel, Joseph, 1942-1943 (Box 339)
      - Williams, Jessie*, 1935-1936 (Box 339)
      - Wright, Ernest H., 1942-1943 (Box 339)
      - Zeissl, Hermann, 1942-1943 (Box 339)
- Series VIII. CEIP Library
  (13 boxes)
  This series comprises an assortment of boooks, pamphlets, periodicals, and typescript reports that were kept in the Endowmen's Library. It includes publications that were sent to the Endowment and kept as reference material, as well as Endowment publications. Printed material can be found througout the other series of the records. This series does not represent the entire CEIP library. For more information on the CEIP library see I.G.
  Series VIII. is organized into three subseries:
  A. CEIP reports and publications
  B. Other publications
  C. Clippings re the Endowment
  - Subseries VIII.A: CEIP reports and publications
    - Addresses... in honor of American professors visiting Geneva... 1925 Sept (Box 339)
    - Certificate of incorporation and by-laws of the Carnegie Endowment in Europe, Inc. 1923 (Box 339)
    - Committee on atomic energy
      - Advisory committee on atomic energy. I. General statetment. II. List of members of the advisory committee... 1945 (Box 339)
      - Atomic energy, its future in power production. 1946 (Box 339)
      - Committee on inspection of raw materials. A conference report on international inspection of radioactive mineral production. 1946 (Box 339)
      - Legal sub-committee. Utilization and control of atomic energy, a draft convention… 1946 (Box 339)
      - Problems of war and peace in the atomic age. Reports and discussion based on proceeedings of a joint conference. 1946 (Box 339)
    - Conference of leaders of American educational enterprises in Europe. Paris, 1948. Report. 1949. (Box 340)
    - Conference on United Nations and Specialized Agency Documentation, Paris, 1948. Report. 1949. (English and French versions.) (Box 340)
    - Dinner for the delegates...section Six of the second Pan-American Congress… 1915 (Box 340)
    - Division of economics and history.
      - Confidential Memorandum and report on German Post-War Police. (Box 340)
      - Preliminary report on researches of the United States Government bearing upon international economic relations. 1938 Nov (Box 340)
      - Procès-verbaux de la conférence convoquée par la Division "Économie politique et histoire." Berne, aout 1911. 1911 (Box 340)
      - Shotwell, James. Memorandum on the preliminary plans for the economic history of the world war. 1920 May 5 (Box 340)
      - Suggestions to contributor to the economic history of the world war... 1920 (Box 340)
    - Division of intercourse and education
      - Babcock, Earle. European Cooperation for Peace. 1933 (Box 340)
      - Beginnings of a Library of International Relations. 1931 (Box 340)
      - Bentley, F.H. The English speaking peoples in the post-war world. 1943 (Box 340)
      - Blaisdell, Donald C. The farmer's stake in world peace. 1935 1937 (Box 340)
      - Booth, Charles Douglas. Cooperation or chaos. 1936 (Box 340)
      - British and American Students Conference on International Affairs. 1931 (Box 340)
      - Butler, Nicholas Murray. The Carnegie Endowment-what it is and does. 1944 (Box 340)
      - Chambers, L.P. A charter for a free world. 1943 (Box 340)
      - Conference on the future policy in Europe of the Divison of Intercourse and Education. 1939 June (Box 340)
      - Do you want prosperity and peaceÀ 1937 (Box 340)
      - Fisher, Edgar J. New thinking necessary for peace. 1937 (Box 340)
      - Hoare, Samuel, Pierrre Laval, and Cordell Hull. Italy and Ethiopia. 1935 (Box 340)
      - Hubbard, Ursula P.
        - A primer on the trade agreements. 1939 1940 (Box 340)
        - The United States and the League of Nations. 1937 (Box 340)
      - Jones, Ann Heminway
        - International Relations. A study course based on the International Mind Alcove Books. 1930 (Box 340)
        - International relatons Clubs, an informal report with practical suggestions for the use of the. 1941 Sept (Box 340)
        - Motion pictures on foreign countries and on international relations. 19321936 1941 (Box 340)
      - List of centros de relaciones internacionales…and List of international relations study groups. 1942 (Box 340)
      - Morrison-Bell, Clive. The European Tariff Walls Map. 1929 (Box 340)
      - Program for peace and prosperity. 1932 (Box 340)
      - Sayre, Francis Bowes. War or world trade whichÀ 1936 (Box 340)
      - Villard, Oswald G. Tariffs and economic disarmament. 1937 (Box 340)
      - Welles, Sumner. A peace for free peoples. 1943 (Box 340)
      - World conference on the textile industry. 1937 (Box 340)
    - Division of International Law
      - Constitution and by-laws of the American Institute of International Law. 1914 (In English and Spanish versions.) (Box 340)
      - Signatures, ratifications, adhesions and reservations to the conventions and declarations of the first and secoond Hague Peace Conferences. 1914 (Box 340)
      - Summary of discussion at the meeting... 1941 Jan 18 (Box 341)